Tony Williams

Tacoma, WA 98444 tony.l.williams88@gmail.com 2537193312

I am a United States Army veteran with over six years of experience as an IT Specialist in an office setting. My technical qualifications include operating and repairing computer components and radio equipment as a means of establishing communications between organizations and clients. My management qualifications include supervising and providing monthly reviews for military personnel assigned to my team, successfully training soldiers to prepare for combat operations, and ensuring that all necessary standard operating procedures were followed properly. Other skills include good verbal communication, self-motivation, and a strong desire to learn and grow.

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

Work Experience

Network Design Systems Drafter

Tercom Construction - Tacoma, WA June 2019 to September 2020

- Utilized Network Design Systems software used by CenturyLink in order to draft and create layouts for fiber optic networks.
- Extensive use of Microsoft Office, with emphasis on Word and Excel.
- Received basic courses on various Fiber Optic equipment and its usage, including multiport service terminals and optical network terminals.
- Conducted quarterly IT training, ranging from Standard Operating Procedures to IT Security Policies.
- Trained new personnel on operating NDS software and ensuring that they understood how to create layouts on their own without supervision.

Warehouse Associate

Costco Optical Lab - Auburn, WA March 2019 to June 2019

- Maintained and monitor various machines used to produce prescription eyewear.
- Attended daily meetings to discuss Employee Policies and standards within the company.

Cashier

September 2017 to March 2019

- Provide customer service and handle all forms of payment.
- Sort donated items and provided product to be sorted by department, cleaned, and priced for the the sales floor.
- Serve as a member of the store safety team, ensuring that company safety procedures were being conducted by all employees.
- Answer phones in a professional manner providing answers if possible, transferring calls, and taking messages.

Broadband Technician

Wave Broadband

February 2017 to September 2017

- Completed assigned work orders within the standard time limit of one hour.
- Provided network service to apartments and condominiums within the Greater Seattle region.
- Worked with equipment such as switches, routers, and broadband modems. Created Cat5, Cat5e, and Cat6 lines to build clients into established networks.

Insurance Agent

June 2016 to January 2017

- Build customer base by providing qualifying customers with information about benefit packages.
- Participated in weekly meetings with company leadership in an effort to promote teamwork and social interaction.
- Meet with potential clients in-home and discuss company policies and guidelines.

Help Desk Technician

U.S. Army

January 2008 to October 2014

- · Conducted troubleshooting, diagnosing, and repairing technical equipment for clients.
- Established IT connections in order to provide communications support for combat units deployed overseas.
- Showed proficiency with the use of technical software including: Microsoft Office, Windows Server, Active Directory, PuTTY, Excel, Outlook and Word.

Education

High School Diploma

Robertsdale High School - Robertsdale, AL

Skills

- Drafting
- Active Directory
- Microsoft Windows Server
- Software Troubleshooting
- Computer Networking

Military Service

Branch: United States Army

Rank: SPC (P)